Register of the Edward Teller Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Audio-Visual Material, 1955-1995.
  - Computer disk, (1), n.d.
    Disk contains text transcript of a discussion about John von Neumann by Denes Nagy (moderator), Edward Teller, Eugene P. Wigner, and Nicholas von Neumann at Arizona State University, undated. Digital use copy available in reading room.
  - Motion picture film reels, 1955-1966
    - 1) Edward Teller addressing unidentified audience, (16mm, silent, Ektachrome), n.d.
    - 2) "Silent Force for Good," The Christopher Program, (late 1950s or early 1960s). Interview by the Reverend Christopher on the good uses of nuclear energy (16mm, sound, black and white, 507 ft.)
    - 3) "Youth Wants to Know," NBC Television, Edward Teller answers questions from students on physics, with Steve McCormick moderating. Includes footage at end of program of Frederick De Hoffman from Los Alamos speaking on the Geneva Convention (16mm, sound, black and white, ca. 1000 ft.), 1955.
    - 4) Appearance, Face the Nation, CBS, Edward Teller answers questions on Chinese nuclear weapons, deployment of defense systems, and international arms control (16mm, sound, black and white, ca. 1000 ft.), 1966 April 3.
    - 5) Duplicate of 4)
    - 6) Untitled 16mm film rolls
    - 7) 30 minute film on Balance of Power, 16mm film reel
  - Phonorecords, 1958-1984
    - 1) Interview, Reader's Digest, 1958 February
    - 2) Appearance, Meet the Press, NBC radio broadcast, 1963 September 1
    - 3) Duplicate of 2)
    - 4) "The Size and Nature of the Universe" and "The Theory of Relativity," Conversations by Edward Teller
    - 5) Duplicate of 4)
    - 6) "Leo Szilard: Inventor of the Atomic Bomb, 1933," Recollections by Leo Szilard, 1984.
- Oversize Material, 1954-1963.
  Drawings and photo collage
  - Drawings depicting Edward Teller, and photo collage depicting him with others, 1954, 1956-1963
- Photographs, 1918-1964
  - Photographic prints (Other 76074)
    - 1 print of a portrait of Edward Teller; 1 print depicting Edward Teller's wife Augusta, 1964; 3 contact sheets of prints depicting Edward Teller (Folder A)
    - 7 prints depicting Edward Teller alone and with others, undated (Folder B)
    - 4 prints depicting Edward Teller and General O'Neill at the SAMSO (Space and Missile Systems Organization) Advisory Group luncheon, April, 1968 (Folder C)
    - 1 print depicting Edward Teller and standing next to his portrait and its artists, Eva and Americo Makk; and 4 prints of Eva and America Makk with President Reagan and of their portraits of Ronald and Nancy Reagan, 1984 (Box D)
    - 1 print depicting participants of the Annual Military Research Associate briefing, March 12, 1969; and 1 print of an unidentified scientist at Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory, undated (Box E)
    - 1 contact sheet of prints depicting Leo Szilard, undated (Folder mF)
    - 5 mounted prints of Los Alamos and Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory; 2 prints depicting Edward Teller with others; 1 print depicting Edward Teller with wife Augusta; 5 prints depicting Edward Teller; 1 print depicting a nuclear explosion; and 1 print depicting a crater in Nevada, undated (Folder fG)
    - 5 albums of prints depicting Edward Teller at the Air Force Academy in Colorado Springs, May 12, 1962; at the 101st anniversary celebration of engineering education at Pennsylvania Military College, Philadelphia, April 2, 1963; with J. Robert Oppenheimer and others, 1964; at the Mayo Clinic Centennial Symposium, Rochester, Minnesota, September 17-18, 1964; in South Africa, September 1973 (Folder fH)
    - 200 slides depicting alternate energy sources, 1918 (Folder Boxes 1-11)
  - Scanned images of photographic prints, circa 1924-1997
    Circa 480 image files (counting both front and reverse) scanned from photographic prints. The original prints are not part of the collection. A spreadsheet provides some descriptive information, but there may not be a one-to-one correlation between items in the spreadsheet and digital images at Hoover
- Incremental Materials (Box 66-654)
  Click on the file name below to download a pdf file of the inventory list for boxes 66-654.
  Incremental Materials Inventory List PDF file